<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rplicate on Algoritma Technical Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/rplicate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rplicate on Algoritma Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rplicate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: I can&#39;t get no ...</title>
      <link>/blog/rplicate-i-can-t-get-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rplicate-i-can-t-get-no/</guid>
      <description>In this third article on Rplicate Series, We will share to you one way to replicate The Economist plot titled &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t get no &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;. The plot making will also demonstrate ways to converting smooth line into linear line, using guides for legend, and adding a text annotation to a plot. The raw dataset used for this graph was obtained from a PDF, so we will also use tibble package to copy-paste the data into R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Cherry Bomb</title>
      <link>/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</guid>
      <description>In this second article on Rplicate Series, We will share to you one way to replicate the plot titled Cherry Bomb from the article &amp;ldquo;Japan’s cherry blossoms are emerging increasingly early, 7th April 2017&amp;rdquo;. The raw dataset used for this graph was obtained from a phenological dataset that was previously collected by Dr. Yasuyuki Aono from Osaka Prefecture University12.
While replicating the plot, we will also learn how to:
 various data pre-processing tricks such as separate a column into several columns, create date data from several columns, and reverse levels of a categorical column create a scatterplot with a custom shape/image as points using geom_smooth() for visualizing trend in the data explore facets and various theme editing on ggplot2  Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Happiness of The Third Age</title>
      <link>/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wonder how far ggplot2 and other packages in R can go for data visualization? Here, we are introducing the Rplicate Series: a series of articles for data visualization in R using ggplot2 and other packages, in aim to replicate The Economist plot. The Economist is an international weekly newspaper that focuses on current affairs, international business, politics, and technology. Along with its article, various graphs were displayed with visuals that is captivating to the eye.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>