<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rplicate on Algoritma Technical Blog</title>
    <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/tags/rplicate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rplicate on Algoritma Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://algotech.netlify.com/tags/rplicate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Bold Axis &amp; Character with ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-bold-axis-character-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-bold-axis-character-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Welcome again to the Rplicate Series! In this 6th article of the series, we will replicate The Economist plot titled &amp;ldquo;Marvellous&amp;rdquo;. In the process, we will explore ways to use bold text and characters for our axes. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in below!
Load Packages These are the packages and some set up that we will use.
library(tidyverse) # for data wrangling library(ggplot2) # for data visualization library(scales) # to customize axes in plot library(ggrepel) # add &amp;amp; customize repelled text library(grid) # create grid &amp;amp; enhance the layouting of plot library(gridExtra) library(png) # import plot to image library(extrafont) # font library # load font from local font_import() # type y when asked to import #&amp;gt; Importing fonts may take a few minutes, depending on the number of fonts and the speed of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Interactive Plot of Coronavirus Survey</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-coronavirus-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-coronavirus-survey/</guid>
      <description>Welcome again to the Rplicate Series! In this 5th article of the series. On this occassion, we will try to replicate the first interactive plot from the FiveThirtyEight article titled How Americans View The Coronavirus Crisis And Trump’s Response. This time you’ll learn how to build an interactive plot using highcharter.
  Library and Setup Below is the required package that we will use during data wrangling and chart creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Gone Baby Gone</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-gone-baby-gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-gone-baby-gone/</guid>
      <description>Welcome again to the Rplicate Series! In this 4th article of the series, we will replicate The Economist plot titled &amp;ldquo;Gone Baby Gone&amp;rdquo;. In the process, we will explore ways to use transformed value as our axes, adding horizontal/vertical line, and making an elbow line (and generally more flexible) annotation for repelled texts.
Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in below!
Load Packages These are the packages and some set up that we will use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: I can&#39;t get no ...</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-i-can-t-get-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-i-can-t-get-no/</guid>
      <description>In this third article on Rplicate Series, We will share to you one way to replicate The Economist plot titled &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t get no &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;. The plot making will also demonstrate ways to converting smooth line into linear line, using guides for legend, and adding a text annotation to a plot. The raw dataset used for this graph was obtained from a PDF, so we will also use tibble package to copy-paste the data into R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Cherry Bomb</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</guid>
      <description>In this second article on Rplicate Series, We will share to you one way to replicate the plot titled Cherry Bomb from the article &amp;ldquo;Japan’s cherry blossoms are emerging increasingly early, 7th April 2017&amp;rdquo;. The raw dataset used for this graph was obtained from a phenological dataset that was previously collected by Dr. Yasuyuki Aono from Osaka Prefecture University12.
While replicating the plot, we will also learn how to:
 various data pre-processing tricks such as separate a column into several columns, create date data from several columns, and reverse levels of a categorical column create a scatterplot with a custom shape/image as points using geom_smooth() for visualizing trend in the data explore facets and various theme editing on ggplot2  Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Happiness of The Third Age</title>
      <link>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://algotech.netlify.com/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wonder how far ggplot2 and other packages in R can go for data visualization? Here, we are introducing the Rplicate Series: a series of articles for data visualization in R using ggplot2 and other packages, in aim to replicate The Economist plot. The Economist is an international weekly newspaper that focuses on current affairs, international business, politics, and technology. Along with its article, various graphs were displayed with visuals that is captivating to the eye.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
