<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidymodels on Algoritma Technical Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tidymodels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidymodels on Algoritma Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidymodels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Classification Model with LIME</title>
      <link>/blog/interpreting-classification-model-with-lime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/interpreting-classification-model-with-lime/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionOne of many things to consider when we want to choose a machine learning model is the interpretability: can we analyze what variables or certain values that contribute toward particular class or target? Some models can be easily interpreted, such as the linear or logistic regression model and decision trees, but interpreting more complex model such as random forest and neural network can be challenging. This sometimes drive the data scientist to choose more interpretable model since they need to communicate it to their manager or higher rank, who perhaps are not familiar with machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to tidymodels</title>
      <link>/blog/tidymodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidymodels/</guid>
      <description>The following presentation is produced by the team at Algoritma for its internal training This presentation is intended for a restricted audience only. It may not be reproduced, distributed, translated or adapted in any form outside these individuals and organizations without permission.
Outline Why tidymodels Matters?  Things we think we&amp;rsquo;re doing it right Things we never think we could do it better  Setting the Cross-Validation Scheme using rsample  Rethinking: Why we need validation?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>