<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualization on Algoritma Technical Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/data-visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualization on Algoritma Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Cherry Bomb</title>
      <link>/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rplicate-series-cherry-bomb/</guid>
      <description>In this second article on Rplicate Series, We will share to you one way to replicate the plot titled Cherry Bomb from the article &amp;ldquo;Japan’s cherry blossoms are emerging increasingly early, 7th April 2017&amp;rdquo;. The raw dataset used for this graph was obtained from a phenological dataset that was previously collected by Dr. Yasuyuki Aono from Osaka Prefecture University12.
While replicating the plot, we will also learn how to:
 various data pre-processing tricks such as separate a column into several columns, create date data from several columns, and reverse levels of a categorical column create a scatterplot with a custom shape/image as points using geom_smooth() for visualizing trend in the data explore facets and various theme editing on ggplot2  Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in below!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rplicate Series: Happiness of The Third Age</title>
      <link>/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rplicate-happiness-of-the-third-age/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wonder how far ggplot2 and other packages in R can go for data visualization? Here, we are introducing the Rplicate Series: a series of articles for data visualization in R using ggplot2 and other packages, in aim to replicate The Economist plot. The Economist is an international weekly newspaper that focuses on current affairs, international business, politics, and technology. Along with its article, various graphs were displayed with visuals that is captivating to the eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Choropleth with Mapshaper and R</title>
      <link>/blog/creating-choropleth-with-mapshaper-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/creating-choropleth-with-mapshaper-and-r/</guid>
      <description>Geospatial is one of the important things in data processing. With geospatial, we can provide information only with the help of maps so that information can be conveyed properly.
There are many types of geospatial that we can do, such as Dot Map, Connection Map, Choropleth, Hexbin Map, and Bubble Map1. Each type of geospatial has its own function, and each of these types also requires different types of information/data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Interactions Analysis using Twinetverse</title>
      <link>/blog/twitter-interactions-analysis-using-twinetverse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/twitter-interactions-analysis-using-twinetverse/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe goal of the twinetverse is to provide everything one might need to view Twitter interactions, from data collection to visualisation. This could be a powerful tool for social media analysis, since it could help visualizing how users communicate with one another on a given topic or how information spreads throughout the Twitter network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>