<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Algoritma Technical Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Algoritma Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Skincare Recommendation System</title>
      <link>/blog/skincare-recommender-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/skincare-recommender-system/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Sys.setenv(RETICULATE_PYTHON = &amp;quot;C:/Users/dyahn/anaconda3/envs/dataanalytics/python.exe&amp;quot;)library(reticulate)py_run_string(&amp;quot;import os&amp;quot;)py_run_string(&amp;quot;os.environ[&amp;#39;QT_QPA_PLATFORM_PLUGIN_PATH&amp;#39;] = &amp;#39;C:/Users/dyahn/anaconda3/Library/plugins/platforms&amp;#39;&amp;quot;)Skincare Recommendation System using Collaborative Filtering (Matrix Factorization)IntroductionHave you ever imagine how Netflix give you recommendation for movies you have never watch before? If you’re familiar with machine learning, you can find the answer. Yappps.. that’s right. The answer is “Recommendation System”.Recommendation system or recommender system is subclass of information filtering system that seeks to predict the “rating” or “preference” a user would give to an item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Song2Vec: Music Recommender</title>
      <link>/blog/song2vec-music-recommender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/song2vec-music-recommender/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}BackgroundThe behavior of musicophiles has changed along with the evolvement of the music industry in the past decades. Previously we conservatively bought music on a compact disc, but now music streaming services are more preferable; such as Amazon Music,Apple Music, Google Play Music, Pandora, Spotify, Youtube Music, to name a few. This is because of the convenience offered by these platforms so that users are able to search their favorite songs right away without having to bother going to the music store physically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Generative Adversarial Network with Keras</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction-to-generative-adversarial-network-with-keras/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction-to-generative-adversarial-network-with-keras/</guid>
      <description>In 2018 a paint of Edmond de Belamy made by machine learning (GAN) was sold for $432,500 in online auction, Christie&amp;rsquo;s. This made Chritie&amp;rsquo;s the first auction house that sell works created by machine learning. On an unbelievable price. What do you think about this ? Will machine learning help us create arts, or will it kill our creativity?
Intro  Is artificial intelligence set to become art’s next medium? - Chritie&amp;rsquo;s</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
